fair-exchange.com 2017-08-11

# P

PRIVACY POLICY
Fair-exchange.com is a brand managed by PDV Limited (“PDV” or “We”) who are specialists in the provision of consumer
data for marketing and market research purposes and We are committed to protecting and respecting your privacy. We
work closely with some of the UK's leading brands to help them target their offers better and help them learn more about
what consumers want from their products. Fair-exchange.com provides manufacturers, retailers and service providers
with the key information they need to serve you better.
As a leading data marketing company, PDV takes the issue of personal data and privacy extremely seriously. PDV is
registered as a Data Controller with the Information Commissioner’s Office, and as such your information will always be
safeguarded through our adherence to the Data Protection Act 1998, and the Privacy and Electronic Communications
Regulations (2003) to ensure that the information you provide to us is safe and only used for the purposes stated in the
opt-in statement and this Privacy Policy.
PDV is also a member of the UK Direct Marketing Association (DMA) and fully complies with its protocols to properly
ensure the correct use of data.
This Privacy Policy (together with our terms of use www.Fair-exchange.com and any other documents referred to on it)
sets out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be processed by us.
Please read the following carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal data and how we will
treat it.
For the purpose of the Data Protection Act 1998 (the “Act”), the Data Controller is PDV Ltd, Company No. 3974954,
Registered in England. Registered Office: Green Heys, Walford Rd, Ross-on-Wye, HR9 5DB a subsidiary of DM plc.
INFORMATION WE MAY COLLECT FROM YOU
Fair-exchange.com is keen to ensure that the principals of our opt-in when your data is collected are clearly explained.
The information you volunteer to Fair-exchange.com and that PDV holds about you, will be shared and used to
appropriately target offers and marketing communication from Fair-exchange.com, from our clients, from our selected
third party partners (including Intela Ltd) and from PDV and its other brands. Marketing communication may be through
email, mailing, telemarketing, SMS/MMS and door-to-door canvassing, depending on which contact channel information
you have volunteered. You may also receive marketing calls via automated voice broadcast over the telephone.
Some questions on our consumer surveys are specific to our named sponsors, and by expressing a positive interest in
their brand or products you are also agreeing to contact from them. By volunteering your phone number you are agreeing
to telephone contact by these named sponsors. You may subsequently need to contact these named sponsor brands
directly if in the future you decide to opt-out of further communication from these brands.
We may collect and process the following data about you:
     •    Your data may be used for analytical purposes. Your data may also be used in conjunction with data we may
          have received from other sources in order to improve personalised and targeted communications, and we may
          share information with other companies for the same reason.
     •    Your data may be shared and combined with other companies who hold your personal data, and we may use
          information from other sources to add to data we already hold. This information may help us to improve our
          ability to service your needs on a personalised basis, by helping us to learn more about you and your purchasing
          habits and allowing us to let you know about offers you might be interested in.
     •    Your data may be used for data validation, enhancement, information verification, suppression, tracing and to
          the extent permitted by law, individual reference or look-up services, by PDV and third parties.
     •    Please remember that you can de-register from Fair-exchange.com at any time (see Deregistration below).
          Furthermore you can request suppression of your details from PDV’s database if you would prefer us not to use
          your information for any of the above.
     •    You can also request to know what personal information PDV holds about you, by writing in person to us at the
          address below asking for subject access request.
© PDV 2011                                                    1

     •    PDV may also receive information about you when you register on one of our affiliate or partner sites, or when
          you take part in a special promotion for one of these affiliates or partners. If you have registered with Fair-
          exchange.com through one of our third party partner sites, it is possible that the third party site may also retain
          your data, but only in accordance with the terms and conditions as published by them on their site.
     •    By filling in forms on our site www.Fair-exchange.com (“our site”). This includes information provided at the
          time of registering to use our site, subscribing to our service, posting material or requesting further services.
IP ADDRESSES AND COOKIES
We may obtain information about your general internet usage by using a cookie file which is stored on your browser or
the hard drive of your computer. Cookies contain information that is transferred to your computer's hard drive. They help
us to improve our site and to deliver a better and more personalised service. Some of the cookies we use are essential for
the site to operate.
Cookie                Name              Purpose                                               More information
ASPXANONYMOUS         www.Fair-         Our cookie tracks a users movement throughout ASP.NET_SessionId=czgal4i13
                      exchange.com      the site and also acknowledges them when they uuocxdqtkjwtbkx
                                        return. Our cookie does not hold any personal
                                        data
                                        This cookie enables us to:
                                             •    Uniquely identify the user to .net, which
                                                  maintains
                                                  copies of the variables from page to
                                                  page as part of a session.
Google analytics      Google            Google Analytics tracks uses cookies in order to Types of cookie __utma __utmb
                                        provide meaningful reports about your site __utmc __utmz __utmx
                                        visitors. Google Analytics cookies do not collect
                                        personal data about your website visitors.
Please note that our advertisers may also use cookies, over which we have no control. You can block cookies by activating
the setting on your browser which allows you to refuse the setting of all or some cookies. However, if you use your
browser settings to block all cookies (including essential cookies) you may not be able to access all or parts of our site.
Unless you have adjusted your browser setting so that it will refuse cookies, our system will issue cookies as soon you visit
our site.
WHERE WE STORE YOUR PERSONAL DATA
The data that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic
Area ("EEA"). It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our suppliers.
Such staff may be engaged in, among other things, the fulfilment of your order, the processing of your payment details
and the provision of support services. By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing.
We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this
privacy policy.
All information you provide to us is stored on our secure servers. Any payment transactions will be encrypted using SSL
technology. Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts
of our site, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share a password with anyone.
Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to
protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our site; any transmission is at
your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to
prevent unauthorised access.
© PDV 2011                                                      2

USES MADE OF THE INFORMATION
We use information held about you in the following ways:
     •    To ensure that content from our site is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer.
     •    To provide you with information, products or services that you request from us or which we feel may interest
          you, where you have consented to be contacted for such purposes.
     •    To carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and us.
     •    To allow you to participate in interactive features of our service, when you choose to do so.
     •    To notify you about changes to our service.
We may also use your data, or permit selected third parties to use your data, to provide you with information about
goods and services which may be of interest to you and we or they may contact you about these by post or telephone.
If you are an existing customer, we will contact you by e-mail, phone, post or SMS with information about goods and
services similar to those which were the subject of a previous sale to you.
If you are a new customer, and where we permit selected third parties to use your data, we (or they) will contact you by
electronic means only if you have consented to this.
If you do not want us to use your data in this way, or to pass your details on to third parties for marketing purposes,
please tick the relevant box situated on the form on which we collect your data the order form or registration form.
DISCLOSURE OF YOUR INFORMATION
We may disclose your personal information to any member of our group, which means our subsidiaries, our ultimate
holding company and its subsidiaries.
We may disclose your personal information to third parties:
     •    In the event that we sell any business or assets we may disclose your personal data to the prospective buyer of
          such business or assets.
     •    If we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation, or in
          order to enforce or apply our terms of use and other agreements; or to protect the rights, property, or safety of
          PDV, our customers, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for
          the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction.
YOUR RIGHTS
You have the right to ask us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes. We will usually inform you (before
collecting your data) if we intend to use your data for such purposes or if we intend to disclose your information to any
third party for such purposes. You can exercise your right to prevent such processing by checking certain boxes on the
forms we use to collect your data. You can also exercise the right at any time by contacting us at PDV, Compliance
Department, 64 Clarendon Road, Watford, WD17 1DA.
Our site may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of our partner networks, advertisers and affiliates.
If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we
do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. Please check these policies before you submit any personal
data to these websites.
DEREGISTRATION
You can unsubscribe from Fair-exchange.com email communications at any time by clicking on the link at the foot of any
email correspondence. Your details will be suppressed, Fair-exchange.com will send no further emails and your details
will no longer be passed onto any third parties for the uses described in this Privacy Policy.
You can also deregister from Fair-exchange.com at any time through the website. Your details will then be suppressed
and Fair-exchange.com will send no further email communication.
To request suppression from PDV completely, please write to us at the address at the bottom of this Privacy Policy, or
email client.services@pdvltd.com
© PDV 2011                                                      3

DATA SECURITY
Although we endeavour to ensure the security of all correspondence, the Internet is not a 100% secure medium.
Therefore, we are unable to guarantee the security of any data you send electronically to Fair-exchange.com and are
unable to accept responsibility for any loss or damage experienced through any loss of confidentiality of your
information.
RIGHT OF TRANSFER
Should Fair-exchange.com or PDV choose to sell or transfer business assets, it is possible that the information we hold
may be transferred as part of the transaction. Fair-exchange.com or PDV may choose to retain a copy of the information
post sale or transfer.
ACCESS TO INFORMATION
The Act gives you the right to access information held about you. Your right of access can be exercised in accordance with
the Act. Any access request may be subject to a fee of £10 to meet our costs in providing you with details of the
information we hold about you.
USEFUL LINKS
As members of the Direct Marketing association we are keen to promote the best interests of consumers and how their
personal data is used. If you would like to know more about how your information can be utilised, how you can restrict its
use, who has access and a wide range of other aspects, we suggest you refer to the following sources:
     •   The Direct Marketing Association; www.dma.org.uk
     •   The Information Commissioner; www.ico.gov.uk
     •   The Citizens Advice Bureau; www.adviceguide.org.uk
For further information please write to:
Compliance Department
Fair-exchange.com
PDV Ltd
64 Clarendon Road
Watford
WD17 1DA
© PDV 2011                                                  4
